This is what we want our model to look like.
我们希望模型结构是这样的
It should take in some inputs and then put those through an embedding layer,
首先接受输入 然后将输入传入嵌入层
which produces some embedded vectors that are sent to a final softmax output layer,
嵌入层生成嵌入向量并将这些向量传递给最终 softmax 输出层
and here's my model definition.
这是模型定义部分
You can see that it's a pretty simple model.
可以看出是一个很简单的模型
First, I'm defining my embedding layer, the self.embed.
首先使用 self.embed 定义嵌入层
This takes n the length of my word vocabulary.
这个参数表示词汇表的长度
This means that it will create an embedding weight matrix that
它将创建一个嵌入权重矩阵
has a row for each of the words in our vocabulary,
词汇表中的每个字词对应一行
and this will output vectors of size n_embed, our embedding dimension.
这个参数表示输出大小为 n_embed（即嵌入维度）的向量
Then, I have a fully-connected layer that takes in that embedding dimension as input,
接着是一个全连接层 它将嵌入维度作为输入
and its output size is also the length of our vocabulary.
输出大小也是词汇表的长度
That's because this output is a series of word class scores
这是因为这个输出是一系列字词类别分数
that tells us the likely context word for a given input word,
表示给定输入字词的潜在上下文字词
and then I've defined a softmax activation layer here.
然后在这里定义了 softmax 激活层
You could have just done this in the forward function too.
也可以在 forward 函数中定义该层级
This is just one solution.
这只是其中一种实现方式
Then at my forward function,
然后我在 forward 函数中
I'm passing in my input X into the embedding layer.
将输入 x 传入嵌入层
This returns are embeddings which moves to our fully-connected layer,
返回嵌入 这些嵌入将进入全连接层
which returns a series of class scores.
并返回一系列类别分数
Finally, a softmax activation function is
最后应用 softmax 激活函数
applied and I'll be left with my log probabilities for context words.
返回上下文字词的对数概率
Below in this training section,
在下面的训练部分
I'm actually going to instantiate this model.
实例化该模型
So here, I've defined an embedding dimension and I've set this to 300,
在这里将嵌入维度设为 300
but you're welcome to experiment with larger or smaller values.
你也可以尝试更小或更大的值
The embedding dimension can be thought of as
嵌入维度可以看做
the number of word features that we can detect,
我们能够检测的字词特征数量
like the length, the type of word, and so on.
例如长度 字词类型等
So, this takes in the entire length of our vocabulary and the embedding dimension,
这里的参数是词汇表的整个长度以及嵌入维度
and I've moved this to a GPU for training.
移到 GPU 上训练
Here, you'll see that I'm using negative log-likelihood loss,
在这里使用了负对数似然损失
and this is because a softmax in combination with
因为 softmax 与负对数似然损失相结合
negative log-likelihood basically equals cross entropy loss.
等效于交叉熵损失
So, this is a great loss for looking at probabilities of context words,
该损失可以查看上下文字词的概率
and I'm using an Adam optimizer,
我使用了 Adam 优化器 这只是我的选择
which is just my go-to and I'm passing in my model parameters and a learning rate.
传入模型参数和学习速率
Then I have my training loop and I've decided to train for five epochs.
下面是训练循环 我决定训练 5 个周期
In this training, actually took a few hours even on GPU,
训练流程在 GPU 上也花费了几个小时
so I'd recommend that you train for a shorter amount of
建议你训练更短的时间
time or wait until I show you how to train more efficiently.
或用后面课程里的更高效的训练方式
So, in my training loop, I'm getting batches
在训练循环里通过调用
of data by calling the generator function that
在上方定义的生成器函数获取批次数据
we defined above and passing in my list of chain words and a batch size.
传入训练字词列表和批次大小
I'm getting my inputs and my target context words,
获取输入和目标上下文字词
and I'm converting them into LongTensor types,
然后将它们转换为 LongTensor 类型
and moving these two GPU if it's available,
如果有 GPU 则将这些移到 GPU 上
and then I'm performing backpropagation as usual,
然后进行反向传播
and passing my inputs into my skip-gram model
将 inputs 传入 skip-gram 模型中
to get the log probabilities for the context words.
获取上下文字词的对数概率
Then I'm applying my loss function to these contexts words and my targets,
然后对这些上下文字词和 targets 应用损失函数
then performing backpropagation and updating the weights of my model,
进行反向传播并更新模型权重
not forgetting to zero out any accumulated gradients before these two steps.
在这两步之前记得清零累积的梯度
Then I'm printing out some validation examples using my cosine similarity function.
然后使用 cosine_similarity 函数输出验证样本
Here, I'm passing in my model and a GPU device,
在这里传入模型和 GPU 设备
and I'm getting back some validation examples and their similarities.
获得验证样本及其相似性
Here, I'm actually using topk sampling to get
在这里使用 topk 抽样
the top six most similar words to a given example.
获取与给定样本最相似的 6 个字词
Here, I'm iterating through my validation examples.
在这里遍历验证样本
I'm printing out the first validation word and then
输出第一个验证字词
the five closest words next to it after a line character,
并在竖线后面输出与该字词最相似的 5 个字词
and here are some initial results.
这些是初始结果
I printed a lot of data after training for five epochs.
在训练 5 个周期后输出了很多数据
At first, these word associations look pretty random.
一开始这些字词之间的关系很随机
We have and, returns,
例如 and | returns
liverpudlians, and so on.
liverpudlians 等
But as I train, I should see that
训练一段时间后
these validation words are getting more and more similar.
这些验证字词越来越相似
If I scroll down all the way to the end of my training,
下拉到训练的结束部分
I can see that similar words are nicely grouped together.
可以看到相似字词组合到了一起
You can see a bunch of number words are grouped together.
这些是数字字词
Here, I have a bunch of animals and mammals grouped in one line,
这些是动物和哺乳动物术语
some lines that are related to states and politics,
有些组合与政府和政治有关
and even lines that are related to a place and a language.
还有些与地点和语言有关
So, it looks like my word2vec model is learning,
看来我的 word2vec 模型取得了学习效果
and I can visualize these embeddings in another way too.
还可以用另一种方式可视化这些嵌入
Another really powerful method for visualization is called t-SNE,
另一个强大的可视化工具是 t-SNE
which stands for t-distributed stochastic neighbor embeddings.
t-SNE 是 t-分布随机近邻嵌入的简称
It's a non-linear dimensionality reduction technique that aims to separate
它是一种非线性降维技巧
data in a way that cluster similar data close together and separates different data.
旨在将相似数据组合到一起并将不同的数据分开
In this case, it's an algorithm that I'm loading in from the sklearn library.
我将从 sklearn 库中加载该算法
I give it the number of embeddings that I want to visualize,
设定要可视化的嵌入数量
and I get these embeddings from the weights of
并从嵌入层的权重中获取这些嵌入
our embedded layer which I'm calling by name from our model.
我将通过名称从模型中调用嵌入层
So, remember that our embedding layer was just named embed,
嵌入层的名称为 embed
and I can get the weights by same model.embed.weight.
我可以使用 model.embed.weight 获取权重
So here, I'm applying t-SNE to 600 of our embeddings,
在这里对 600 个嵌入应用 t-SNE
and this is what this t-SNE clustering ends up looking like.
t-SNE 聚类最终看起来是这样的
We can actually see that similar words are grouped together.
可以看出 相似的字词组合到了一起
Here we have east, west, north, and south.
例如 east、west、north 和 south
If we look to the right, we can see some musical terms: rock,
在右边可以看到一些音乐术语
music, album, band, and song.
rock、music、album、band 和 song
Lower down, we can see some religious terms,
下面是一些宗教术语
some colors over here,
这里是一些颜色术语
some academic terms: school, university, and college.
这里是一些关于学校的术语：school、university 和 college
On the left side here,
在左边
I can see clusters of the months in the year and it looks like a few integer values here.
有一些月份术语 这里是一些整数值
So, this clustering indicates that my word2vec model has worked.
这些聚类表明我的 word2vec 模型成功了
It learns to generate embeddings that hold semantic meaning,
它学会生成包含语义信息的嵌入
and this also gives us a cool way to visualize the relationships between words in space.
并且我们可以通过这种方式直观地可视化字词之间的空间关系
So, one problem with this model was that it took quite a while to train,
不过这个模型有个问题 它训练时间很长
and next I'm going to address that challenge.
接下来我们将解决这一问题